[music]
The Paris fashion [music] show begins.
Every day for a week, the catwalk will
be full of floating color. The designers
have cut their cloth to the shape of
another spring. At its best, it's art.
Often, it's theater. Always it's a
business.
>> But what business is it of mine? I
thought fashion was frivolous until I
visited the Soviet Union and realized
that people deprived of frivolity think
of nothing else. That made me think
again. Then the famous photographer
Terrence Dunovan told me that if I
really wanted to see how serious the
fashion scene was, I should go with him
to Paris and make a movie. He brought
the camera, I took the pencil, and we
went to the fashion show.
The fashion show begins with the veteran
designer Giovanchi. It's late autumn
outside, but the models addressed 6
months ahead. They've flown in from all
over the world. The fashion
correspondents have flown in just behind
them. Both groups of ladies suffer from
permanent jet lag and either never have
periods or else have the same one all
the time, thereby qualifying for the
super tampac circuit. The cast and the
audience combined to form the fashion
show.
Meanwhile, Jabashi's collection is going
down well with the assembled experts. I
think I can see why. Although, in
another week, I hope to have something
better than Instinct to go on.
>> See you again. How are you?
>> How are you? Backstage, Gioveni accepts
homage from the American buyers, known
collectively as the boys from Blooming
Dales.
>> So nice to see you again.
>> Nice to see you.
>> He's from Blooming. How are you?
>> Blooming confus.
>> And this is where the kissing has to
start.
>> Hi. It's great to see you. He's
fine. He's fine.
>> Do you think it will be a successful
collection in commercial terms? Can you
tell
>> just from the way it was? Can you tell
just from the way it was received?
>> Uh, you know, you never know. This is
what is important is the reaction of the
buyers.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, is a early show.
>> I was watching the buyers and they were
clapping.
>> And you know, I I work in that direction
to to please the buyers and the
customer. What's most important to you?
Better or
>> uh both. Now this is very interesting
because it's difficult to make ready to
wear.
>> Yeah.
>> To have short quantity of fabrics to
make to try to make a beautiful dress
and a beautiful effect.
>> After a sleepless night with my head
full of music and swinging skirts, I was
back into the action. There was a day
when hot couture was all that counted
and you had to be Jackie Kennedy to wear
a work of art. Then ready to wear took
off. Most of the designers are men, but
there have always been a few conspicuous
exceptions. Sonar Kill isn't out to
dress the rich, although she might very
well get rich herself dressing all the
dynamic ladies who like wearing her
clothes.
She lives in a garrett, but as garretts
go, it's got a lot going for it. More of
a temple, really.
Sonia is a deep thinker about her
calling. The high priestess pronounces.
I think the the first act for a woman to
be close it's to look at her in a mirror
and to understand what she is and what
what is the image she want to to have
she want to to project and after that
she can mix any closes but only if they
know how to do that and it's for that I
speak about the mirror because they have
to know them they have to understand
what they are they have to understand
what they want to show and what they
want to hide of their own figure.
[music]
[applause]
Pilots in the Women's Liberation Air
Force. And already I've learned my first
lesson about ladies threads. Don't judge
them by the funny hats and the mad
makeup. The frocks are what count and
Sonia are good solid stuff. Unlike her
metaphysics which tend towards the
cloudy,
>> I don't think that the women they have
to ask to people like me the way to be
dressed. It's a question of herself. I
make closes and I make them in my way
but not in the way of the other women.
And naturally I know everything about
women because I am a woman. I know what
a woman need and but in fact in fact I
don't know what each woman needs. I
prepare for her all the uniform of that
and after she have to to make her own
choice.
[music]
>> [music]
>> The way to be for women to be for me
very interesting
is the way to use the movement and
gesture. Because if we know that the
women they are dressed in the same way,
the same shape, in the same style, they
have to be different not with the
clothes but with the gesture, with the
movement
with the closes.
You have to give the impression to be
nude.
to catch men. It's the first act for a
woman. They do that naturally. But the
way to be dressed, it's not the purpose
to catch men. The purpose is to
understand you yourself by the inside.
My own purpose being to find out more
about the closers. I headed off to the
exhibition tent at Port Deersai for the
next big show by Tierry Mule. From the
outside, Port Deersai has the same charm
as court without the elegance. But sir
closers show up well in the white light
and anyway business is business. By now
the executive jets have followed the
airliners into Shal Deaul airport. The
boys from Bloomingdales have been joined
by their boss.
>> Bloomingdales. Uh at this show at the
Pret uh we have some 20 people in Paris
and we will probably at our retail
invest three to4 million here.
>> Handouts in every language keep the
present buyers updated. People speaking
strange tongues drop out of the
stratosphere. Nancy Piltchure of
Australian Vogue.
>> Australians travel abroad a lot. I mean
they have the need when you live down
there. You really feel as though in
order to make a contact you need to come
away. So Australians come come to the
prep, you know, from a business point of
view a lot to buy and take back to
Australia. I mean, we report in the
magazine in Vogue, um, what's happening
currently, but, you know, equally
enough, there are a lot of people here
from Australia buying clothes and taking
them back to sell.
>> How many shows have you managed to see
in Paris?
>> Yeah, they're all they're all with
they're all with this television group.
It's a little group.
>> English art students crash through
security.
>> How many shows have you managed to see?
about I don't know about three or four.
>> And you've all done them all by this
extraordinary method of bluffing your
way through the way we just did them.
>> Terrific.
>> Judging from Muglair's reputation,
they've come to see someone who's going
to make them look restrained. But
Muglare's notorious extremism has the
backing of the most influential of the
fashion correspondents, Hib Dorsey of
the New York Herald Tribune.
>> There's another breed of people who are
here to have to make fashion progress.
And you cannot progress by doing one
raffle after another. You know, you've
got to take into account the the world
in which we live, the conditions in
which we live, the traveling and I think
the Muglare clothes have that answer
>> Muglare was going nowhere until
recently, but after Blooming Dales took
his whole collection to New York, he
became an event. What did he think of
the American competition?
>> Well, some of them have very strong uh
image,
you know, they they have a direction
very strong. They work very well on
that. It's different. In France, we work
much more on uh we take more risk. We do
more we make the fashion going uh on a
you see going
>> forward.
>> Yes.
>> More.
>> Think there's any chance of New York
ever rivaling Paris as a fashion center?
>> Well, in Paris we have a real um base of
fashion. You know it's a it's a
tradition to try all this tradition for
us. For a long time we have all this uh
knowledge that
Muglare sounds halfway between a mugger
and a bugler. And certainly the closes
show a distinct element of military
violence. Muglare just loves uniforms.
If it has ever occurred to him that
Hitler thought the same way, he hasn't
let it bother him.
KGB interrogators or Chinese
paratroopers who need a little number
for evening wear should place their
orders. Now
you try flying a B-52 over her and
you'll get a SAM 7 right up your tail.
writing a letter for help
with Muglare. The jock strap finally
makes it as a work of art. Note the coil
of rope around the gentleman's waist to
hang himself with if the party gets
dull.
>> Isn't that Marie Helvin?
After only two shows, I'm starting to
notice that the same girls are cropping
up all the time.
[music]
[screaming]
>> It gets to be fun spotting the familiar
faces.
>> That's definitely Marie Hilvin, which
probably means that Jerry Hall isn't far
away. Jerry and Marie are pals.
Current top money earning model in the
world, Jerry Hall.
[music]
[singing]
>> Dragon Lady demands sacrifice.
You kiss it.
>> On Jerry, it looks good, but she'd look
good in a body bag. I could just about
see how my dislike of Muglare's designs
might have been a regressive male
chauvinistic desire to keep women
wrapped in ruffles. Later, I found his
creations hard to forget, but then I
felt the same way about Sinusitis.
Anyway, the press broke his way and so
did the buyers, which probably means
that before too long, some female in
your family will be wearing a blue denim
germ warfare suit with a leopard skin
pattern polyine poncho. Maybe that's the
price of liberation. It could be that
all those pretty frrills ever did was to
keep women in their place. If your
girlfriend treads on your head with a
jacket, at least you'll know she's
wearing her clothes instead of her
clothes wearing hers.
>> After years in the wilderness, Muglare
is at last an overnight success.
>> Takes time, but it comes like that. I
don't know why. I always did the same
thing and one season it just everybody
discover it and said ah we sell it well
we love it and everybody likes it
and I don't know just came like that
but Muglare's way forward is not the
only road the great designers can still
flatter women without patronizing them
for the house of Khloe Carl Laggerfeld
embodies the ideal cocktail of tradition
and inventiveness he's drawn destroying
his friend Sonar Rikio.
>> How do you feel about working in a a
medium which is essentially here today
and gone tomorrow? Anyway, here today
and gone the day after tomorrow. I mean,
don't you want to build something
permanent? What are you building that's
permanent?
>> Nothing. I like to destroy things
because if you need to destroy things,
you have to build again. I Who wants to
have one thing built and then wait for
the rest of the day? What I like in
fashion is you do it again and you do it
again and you do it again. You age
perhaps quicker than everybody else
because you live six months ahead. But
that's funny about fashion, you know, to
do to destroy. To do, to destroy.
>> Explain to us what's involved
>> in the fitting. You know, the only thing
involved is to see if the dress is doing
right or not. This dress has nearly
already finished. It's the last fitting.
So, I have to see the proportion, the
length, and and everything.
>> Is this for the collection?
>> I'm afraid it will.
You know, if you make actually make a
whole group of dresses, you make one and
then you make it with with a narrow
skirt, with shorts, with pants. In fact,
the new thing is the proportion of this
with this square shoulder thing. But
what must be as easy to wear as a
t-shirt, not like a stiff sophisticated
dress. She must forget the dress in the
moment she had it on her. If you don't
forget the dress, that something was not
right in the dress. With this new uh two
floor arrangement, the large skirt looks
even shorter than the dress really is. I
think what's dimly for the moment is the
medium length ankle length and short is
okay. What ba is the the knee covered
length looks really not right for the
moment. Has to be a little shorter. Huh.
>> Has to tell me if she feels everything
okay, if she can move and think like
this. All the technical details. That's
why I think it's much more intelligent
to fit with on assistant than on
professional models because they don't
care about the dress and they don't know
nothing about dresses. If this wouldn't
fit, she would tell me instantly.
>> Does it manner?
>> Does it fit Jin? [snorts]
>> Yes.
>> The professional models are all signed
up with agencies of which one of the
largest is run by Jeanluke Brunell.
>> Jean Luke, this I'm just looking at this
rotary filing system of yours in front
of you and it's got the name of hundreds
and hundreds of girls in it. How many
are there all all together? Roughly
>> we have u 84 girls all together
>> and like 35 40 working all the time in
Paris.
>> Yeah.
>> And the other ones are girls that we
represent that are in the states or in
England like girls like Jhole or Margo
Emigingu or Lisar
>> they get onto your filing system they've
made it
>> normally. Yes.
>> Yeah. Normally yes.
>> Yeah. Normally yes. And we see it very
in two three months we see if they can
make it and if they can't then we try to
>> tell them to go either back to school or
back to college or
>> but we don't keep girls just for having
girls hanging around.
>> And do they go when you tell them to go?
Do they go back to college?
>> Sure they understand.
>> What are they after?
>> Well, they're after glamour actually.
They want to to have,
you know, it's always like a little
dream, you know, to to be a model
because when you make it, you it's a
fantastic first. It's a good job and
when you make it, it becomes great. You
have girls making like $150,000 a year.
You have some girls like we have some
girls of 30 years old and they still
make um
um
pounds a day.
>> Do they marry rich men? Does that sort
of thing happen?
>> It can happen,
>> but I mean we don't provide the husband
picture. [laughter]
>> Models come in all flavors. Some of them
are fairly clearly plugged into a
special wavelength where there isn't
much torque between tracks. But some of
them are sober and industrious. None
more so than Jerry, who banks her money
the day she makes it and owns a ranch
called Lonely Oak in Texas. She's on the
catwalk in every major city in the world
and she'll do three shows a day in Paris
alone.
>> How do you fit them all in? I mean, do
you do you stay made up between shows or
what?
>> Yeah.
>> And you run.
>> You run a lot. Yeah.
>> And you run for a whole week?
>> Yeah. I'm doing 19.
>> Yeah. 19 shows. That's incredible. How
do you feel at the end of the week?
>> Rich.
>> I like them all. Most of them have the
same career prospects as a raindrop, but
they shine. When you're among them, you
become so used to beauty that you get
interested in personality all over
again. You want to hear the flawless
face talk before you fall for it.
Backstage at Chloe, I was riding amongst
a forest of real eyelashes so long they
look false. The loveliest of all the
level-headed Swedes is called Ganilla
Linlat.
>> I don't know. I thought it was funny to
try.
>> Yeah. And
>> I didn't know if I would succeed or not.
It was just a challenge.
>> And you came to Paris?
>> I came to Paris. Yeah.
>> And when did you know you were
successful?
When the phone started to ring, huh?
>> When Yeah. When you start to work every
day.
>> Yeah.
>> When you can say no. When you have to
say no to some jobs, then you're
successful.
>> You enjoy it still?
>> Oh, I love it. Yeah.
>> Marci Hunt is a smart American.
>> What's it like with 10,000 guys watching
you? Do you forget it?
>> Yes, I do in a way. I mean, I enjoy it.
I enjoy the fact. I mean, I think that
you have to show off the clothes to the
best advantage. I mean, that's the main
reason why we're there, to look
beautiful and to show off the clothes.
And I I have a lot of fun. I think it's
exciting.
>> It depends, you know, if you have
beautiful dress on, if you look nice,
you have a nice hair do, nice makeup,
you look you feel feel fine.
>> If you have a lousy dress on, you feel
awful.
>> Bursting with creativity, Carl
Laggerfeld is revving up for the off.
He's just thought of something. Hats
like ice cream cones.
But if the girls are to wear pointed
hats, they will have to have pointed
hairstyles.
>> Okay.
Have
>> you got the running order in your head
or is someone going to tell you that
every time you come off to change?
>> Um, no. We don't have to remember
because actually each girl has her own
clothes, her own set of clothes, which
makes it much easier.
>> You got your own dresser waiting for you
when you come off? Yes, absolutely.
Because sometimes there are very small
buttons or there's straps on the shoes
that have to be tied. So, everything has
to be done very quickly.
The
>> show goes on assembling itself before
the odd gaze of your reporter.
>> Now, who's got a conical head?
The tong dwellers gear up for the
conical concept.
>> Unaware that the human head is being
reshaped backstage, the public gathers.
Here come the British art students
again. Who are they pretending to be
this time?
>> And once again, they crash straight
through.
At this stage, I was all set to make a
flight exit and take up my appointed
place front of house. But Dunovan
advised me to stay quiet, stick around,
and blend into the backstage scenery.
This turned out to be a very rewarding
course of action.
Lena didn't come. No one
I called her.
[applause]
[music]
>> [applause]
>> One of Carl's invaluable assistants
directs operations from the control
tower.
[music]
The
>> conicle hat concept was by now in a very
advanced stage of research and
development.
So they put on.
>> But of course, the buyers weren't
looking at the hats. They were looking
at the latest version of that long,
soft, flowing Chloe line that goes on
selling forever. REASON.
>> If any of you guys out there are asking
how it feels to be back here, the answer
is nice. It feels very nice to be back
here. Beyond that, I haven't examined my
feelings because I have a lurking
suspicion that if I smile too hard, car
will go ape and sling me out.
[music]
>> There are people that will investigate.
They'll insinuate, intimidate,
complicate.
>> Suddenly, it struck me that there was
something else Kyle could have done with
the hats.
But it was too late to tell him. The
show was already airborne.
[music]
on [music and singing]
your eyes. [music and singing]
Get your [music] hands on my
busy [music]
head. One step up, one step back. Lo
[music]
>> [music]
[applause]
>> It's a big hit for Carl. He might have
made pointed heads fashionable next
year, but the clothes is themselves are
classic stuff.
[applause]
>> [applause]
>> Back he goes to face the kisses.
>> So what do you do now? You sit back and
wait for the orders to flood in.
What do you do now? Just
>> relax.
>> I have other things to do. You know,
>> he had too. The Paris fashion show was
only half over.
>> If Karen had stayed in Finland, this
wouldn't be happening to her. Olivier is
making her up for the Paris fashion
show. Anybody, any ladies can be
beautiful with makeup. Really?
>> Any anybody any age.
>> Oh, of course. No age for to be
beautiful.
>> Yeah.
>> Sure. Not
>> it's easy with a young and is more
excited to do around 40 and 50.
>> [music]
>> I was
But enough of that.
The Paris Fashion Week is about half
over and we're backstage before Unaro's
collection. Unaro is a diehard
reactionary who likes women to look
pretty. He learned the job from the hem
up. His father was a tailor.
>> You can't just be a designer. It is not
enough. It's good. You have to be. But
if you are and if you are professional,
if you know how to cut it, how to do it,
how to to to put things together,
at that moment you could be maybe a
designer.
While designers like Muglare are welding
the brave women into camouflage frogman
outfits, designers like Unaro offer the
cowards a well-cut, clinging refuge.
It's a million-doll formula. Instead of
the portai tent, Unaro chosen a salon
with little gold chairs for the press
and buyers.
>> I always prefer to have a specific
[music] ambiance to show my work. I
really don't want to make enormous show
with a with a lot of girls. I prefer to
have a specific ambiance with [music]
much more personality.
Thank you so much.
[music]
Unarro's design philosophy goes back to
when Eve clad her nakedness.
>> Seduction is the main word. Seduction.
Seduction. Seduction.
>> It's probably a bit corny to say so, but
I think he seduced me.
>> [music]
>> No one tears the outcome.
Just believe it will always be
the heart in your hand.
When we show [music] collection, it's
always a sort of adventure. You know, we
are never sure about the result. Never.
The problem is not to be successful
once.
The promise to be successful always.
[applause]
>> Unaro's show is a big hit. Lulled by the
Philly vision of his conservatism, I
craved adventure.
The Japanese designers are more daring
in keeping with their strong tradition
of landing their naval aircraft on the
enemy's capital ships. Their leader is
called Kenzo and he's some kind of
genius.
>> We make design and for not only one
material.
>> Ah, I see. Yeah,
>> we have.
>> Show us the material.
>> If he was less talented, he would never
get away with his sake crazed
eclecticism.
>> Kenzo came to Paris from Tokyo in the
late60s. absorbed the whole history of
western fashion all at once and made a
kaleidoscope of it. His sense of color
is so highly developed that he can sew
rose petals on a tartan.
>> This is the first pattern with
>> and
the firmy heads is called [__] and it's a
success story on the scale of the zero
fighter except that what Kenzo does
doesn't hurt you.
>> I see. So this is this is the pattern
and this is the real material of the
actual and and will we see we see that
one at the collection?
>> Yes.
>> I hope so.
[applause]
>> [applause]
>> reasons to be chill.
>> The jab show happens in its very own
tent covering the whole of the plaster
victto with the catwalk running straight
out of the front door of Kenzo's shop.
The clothes immediately strike even a
tiny eye like mine as being exuberant
like nobody else's. Kenzo's single most
inspired innovation, however, is to feed
the champagne to the models before the
show instead of after. The result is
banzai boogie.
It's easy to be cheerful.
>> So Yoko is the bride. Madame Butterfly
goes west.
[applause]
>> Kenzo's show is a hit, but he'd probably
be lionized even if he'd sent them out
wearing cardboard boxes. Everybody loves
him. And there's a hill of champagne
bottles back there.
>> You happy?
>> Yeah.
>> Yes, I'm very happy.
>> Tell the world you're happy.
>> I'm very happy.
>> Somewhere in the background, Kenzo's
business partners are crouching with
faces lit green by the light of pocket
calculators. But where Kenzo is, it's
always a party.
>> What was it like back here?
>> Perfect.
>> Perfect. It is. I'm telling you.
The week comes to a peak with Eve San
Lauron. His towering status is reflected
by the security checks you have to get
through to get in. Everybody admires San
Lauron's talent and hates his business
manager, Miss Su Ber, who repeatedly
once kicked a catwalk photographer in
the face.
For the photographers, the catwalk at
the Paris collections is the toughest
assignment after guerrilla warfare. They
all have atrocity stories.
>> The trick is to come very early. So you
establish position. It's like a chess
game. And he came very early for show
and for some reason the security didn't
want to let let him in
and he insisted he wanted to get in. So
I think he put he put his his case on
the other side of the barricade. The
other one took barate and he's starting
to to fight and he got um you know
tookie walkie on the head. Alert to the
possibility of being hit by a talky
walkie, the photographers dig in under
the catwalk. As always, Beer underlines
San Lauron's prestige by making the
audience wait again. As always, they
mutter impreations. And again, as
always, the wait turns out to be worth
it. [applause]
[music]
>> Love say that in
number 68.
[applause]
So I say it to you
like the French people do
because it's also
self love number 69.
A week ago, I could have told you this
was exceptionally good, but not why.
Now, I think I can see some of the
reasons.
>> Everything seems to flow like smoke.
>> The line is simple, the finish is
flawless, and there's that air of
authority you get from a first class
artist in any medium. Just by putting on
the closers, the girls have caught San
Lauron's sense of superiority. You can
see it in their eyes. You'd be shy than
ever about asking one of them out for a
hamburger in a movie.
>> [applause]
>> At this point, the lights conked out.
Some of the more battleweary
photographers went on getting shots of
the darkness. Everyone hoped Beer would
come out and do his nut, but he double
crossed his public by remaining sane.
>> [applause]
>> We are very sorry. Thank you very much.
[music]
>> The lights conked out again. Maybe Beer
had kicked the electrician.
>> But the show went on to its inevitable
triumph. Heat. Heat.
[applause]
[music]
>> [applause]
[applause]
[music]
>> The master materializes.
Eve Sandleron. [applause]
>> [applause]
[applause]
>> backstage. They start kissing Eve's face
away like water on a soft rock.
>> Oscillatory attrition is the designer's
occupational hazard.
>> Meanwhile, your intrepid reporter Braves
Beer,
>> you were very cool when the lights went
out. Very cowboy. Everybody, what can we
do?
>> Put the clothes with something.
>> You know, it's a French organization.
>> Exactly. Brilliant.
>> Okay. We are very good for food and wine
and maybe fashion, but not for life.
>> Still chewing Eve's face.
>> You enjoy it?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I'm relieved it's over.
>> Yeah. Really?
>> Yeah. I got to go home and cut my money
now.
>> Did you enjoy that?
>> Oh, yeah. [laughter]
>> You enjoy it still after all these
years?
>> Yeah. I love it.
>> So, what do you do next? What are you
going to do now?
>> I'm finished now.
>> Yeah. Were you taking pictures of girls
and clothes in Russia?
>> No. Never.
>> Never.
>> Aren't there fashion shows there?
>> Yes. But it's for a very close society.
Not for so many people like here. I
mean, it's for clothes, but you can get
an invitation. But there
>> So, it's not democratic in Russia.
>> Not really.
>> No. You see, anyway, if you have money,
you can't buy what they produce. I mean,
they don't produce uh for shops.
So when you got here and you saw one of
these shows, what was your first
impression?
>> I like it.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Picasso's daughter Paloma joins the
kissing queue.
>> I just love this collection most of all.
I mean this collection was really the
greatest of all and um I must say Eve is
always the best.
>> What's he got that the other guys
haven't got?
>> Uh he's sure he knows exactly what he's
doing. I think he really, you know, he's
so sure of of what he's doing, the
colors and he can play around, you know,
with colors and shapes anyway because he
can't go wrong.
>> What do you think your father would have
thought of of today? Was he interested
in
>> Oh, he was interested in everything
that's, you know, that's being done. He
loved to dress. I mean, it was a great
great dresser. He would always dress
with very extravagant clothes and very
strong colors and I'm sure he would have
enjoyed, you know, a fashion show. So
shy that he arrives in the boot of a car
before a show and has been known to go
into exile before it is over. Eve
nevertheless granted your reporter an
interview.
>> You prefer designing for summer or
winter?
>> Summer.
>> Yes.
>> Why is that?
>> Because it's synonymous of
holidays.
>> When did you start thinking of the
collection? When did you start thinking
of your
>> This one? Two weeks ago.
>> Yeah. Really? So soon?
I was the only one who didn't get
kissed.
>> Eve San Lauron was still top of the
heap. But if I thought I'd seen
everything, I was wrong. The designer
who really startled everyone was Claude
Montana. For years, Montana had been
turning out the kind of schmutter where
the lady looked as if she'd walked out
of the frizz parlor with a haird dryer
still on her head and had put on
American football armor under her
combinations. His frocks were strictly
for fashion slaves. No one denied he had
talent. What they denied was that any
woman with all her marbles would ever
consent to wear his clothes except at
gunpoint.
>> I think if I had listened to all the
people at the beginning when I started,
I would have quit to do something else.
So it's just I think you have to really
stick to
your own ideas and personalities. It's
just the only way I think just to be
honest with yourself and do really what
you feel like doing.
Keep [music]
[music]
going.
Claude's hats were still pretty weird,
and Olivia had been at the girl's faces
with six different kinds of aerosol, but
the frock suddenly looked possible. You
could almost imagine your sister wearing
them if your sister didn't mind stopping
the traffic.
The Women's Liberation Lifeboat Service
>> [music]
[applause]
[music]
>> The Women's Liberation Navy. Admiral
Debbie in command.
[music]
[applause]
>> [music]
>> I love the show. By now, I'd learned
that fashion doesn't just mean things
being thought up, hoisted on helpless
victims, and then forgotten. These
dresses will always look good. There is
such a thing as a lasting image made of
cloth.
[applause]
>> [music]
>> Not every woman can afford to look like
this, but there was a time when almost
none of them could. The new styles
filter down and change everything. And
as hems and collars eb and flow, we
measure time. What better to measure it
by.
The bride wore black. Watch out next
year for a white funeral outfit.
[music]
The great thing about the fashion show
is that even a convicted dingbat like
Claude can suddenly turn out something
women want to put on. It was like that
in the cave. There was always a man who
ducked out from hunting animals and sat
around making cocktail frogs out of the
skins. He spent too much time with the
ladies, but how bad is that? Monta has
always been out to stun the audience,
but this time he stunned them nicely.
He doesn't look as if he could hit very
hard in a fight, but he sure knows how
to make them happy.
The whole world is fighting to get at
him and to discuss his collection, which
has been a triumphant success. We're
among the privileged who have managed to
penetrate to the inner sanctum behind
him. They're actually people trying to
break down the doors to get in here
outside. Success in this sort of thing
is 100% or it's nothing. And he's just
had a most magnificent show. And now
he's so overwhelmed by the reception
he's getting that he's actually gone
into hiding.
>> Who claude? Is he hiding?
>> I don't know how he could have got lost.
Those padded shoulders of his are hard
to miss.
I
>> think his divine collection is so great.
so inspirated and full of imagination
and color
>> and actually very wearable. I mean, he's
actually
>> I think because he's very extreme, but
he's so uh perfect, you know, is
flatter, very flattering for the for the
for our lady. It's fantastic.
>> Yeah, but they look great.
>> Yeah.
>> And where do you think Mont is hiding at
the moment?
>> Where he is?
>> I'm looking for him.
>> I'm just told he's actually over here.
His physical presence has now been
announced and we're going to try and get
at him for a second.
>> Well, why you so shy? Hey, you've had a
great triumph.
>> We would.
>> The girls The girls love the clothes.
They
>> already the fashion correspondents have
risen out of Paris like locusts from a
sweet cactus and scattered to a thousand
offices around the world. The boys from
Bloomingdales are at the Crazy Horse
Saloon planning their strategy for the
hard bargaining that starts tomorrow.
The models stay on for one night's
dancing as all the people of the Paris
fashion show come to the ball. Most of
these girls are new in town. They sleep
two or three to a flat, man the phone in
shifts, and those long gowns are rented.
The silly ones will sniff the rich man's
poison. Most of them will go home after
a while and get married, not necessarily
to the local tycoon. The Swedes, for
example, tend to have policemen for
boyfriends. There are guys on point duty
in Stockholm who go home every night to
women who look like dreams. A few of the
girls will make it to the big money
where the lights shine white for as long
as skin stays young.
My week at the fashion show took me a
long way. I saw how the great designers
take the human impulse to show off and
control it until it turns to style. I
learned a bit more about giving rain to
whatever is the opposite of masculine in
my own nature. I met a lot of beautiful
girls and made friends of them instead
of a fool of myself.
I went out shopping with Jerry Hall and
I danced at the ball with Marie Helvin.
I learned to look at Zakloas with a
certain respect even when they seemed
crazy. Most of them will go out of date
one day, but so will I. And meanwhile,
who's to say that all the world's women
who care about looking good are pleasing
just themselves? When is innocent
pleasure ever wasted? Koko Chanel, who
designed a little suit that helped begin
to set women free, once said, "Luxury is
a necessity that starts where necessity
stops."
My own view is that God when he finished
resting on the seventh day went to sleep
and dreamed Paris.
Where is everyone?
Now listen, you sit down. I'm going to
give you some advice. If you want to get
somewhere, you want to be [music]
somebody, stand up. Stand up and get it
again.
>> Don't want you.
I want you to get it get
wor.
Just be [music] sure you got a real
conviction.
Get it.
>> [music]